Satguru Saran Satsangi P.

Lead User Experience Researcher

Website: http://psssatsangi.com/ Email: satsangi77@gmail.com

Phone: +13177021793

Summary

3+ years' of experience as User Experience Researcher and Designer, partnering with internal and external stakeholders to design, build, improve and expand the user experience. A proven history of creating cutting edge interface designs and information architectures for web and mobile applications through a user-centered design process by constructing screen flows, research, prototypes, and wireframes.

Experience

Lead UX Researcher | Walmart

March 2019- Present

(through Flexton Inc.)

I am part of Associate Talent Product Design team at Walmart Home office. My key responsibilities include leading qualitative and quantitative research studies, Ideation sessions and guiding the team throughout the UX process.

Product Designer | New Wisdom, LLC

October 2017- December 2018

I worked as a designer for two Augmented Reality projects. For one project, I won the best project award from Indiana University. For the second project, I worked remotely and collaborated with dev. and 3D modeling teams. My key responsibilities include designing a new UI for a E.com website, which sells sunglasses fit overs. I integrated a Virtual Try-on feature in the ecom. website for customers to try the fit overs using their webcam at home.

Graduate Research Assistant (UI/UX) | Indiana

January 2017- Dec 2018

University

I lead the UX team in COMET LAB. My key responsibilities include creating wireframes, prototyping, storyboarding and conducting qualitative and quantitative research.

UI/UX Designer | The Workshops

June 2014- July 2014

I worked as a UX Designer for implementing a website for the NGO, which is used for training Egyptian women in different fields. My responsibilities include requirement gathering, designing wireframes and prototyping, Information Architecture, user testing and collaborating with the developer.

Education

MS Human Computer Interaction Indiana University, Indianapolis January 2017 - December 2018

B.Tech Information Technology Gayatri Vidya Parishad College of Engineering August 2011 - May 2016

Skills

Design

Visual Design
Story Boarding
Wire-framing
Interactive Prototyping
Sketching
Information Architecture

Research Mothods

Affinity Mapping
Heuristic Evaluation
Usability Testing
Focus Analysis
Persona
Cognitive Walkthrough
A/B testing
Contextual Inquiry
Competitive Analysis
Card Sorting

Design Tools

Adobe Creative Suit Sketch InVision Figma Marvel

Programming

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, MySQL

Others

Jira, Plant, Zeplin